losif V.

Software Engineer

London, (UK)

in iosify iosify iosify

SUMMARY

I am a Senior Software Engineer with experience in creating complete projects from scratch to production in Node.js and Laravel. I write code as clean as possible so that the next dev will be happy to maintain it and the junior will quickly grasp it. Curious by nature, I'm always learning new things.

SKILLS

LanguagesFrameworksAdminNode.jsTypescriptPHPLaravelExpressServerlessAWSTerraformCI / CDSoliditybashHardhatDockerShell Scripting

Currently learning

Java NextJS T3 Stack

WORK EXPERIENCE (4)

Aug 2018 - Current

Contractor Software Engineer at

Provided contractor services through my own LTD, Casa4, in between other roles. The following is a list of the most notable projects, specializing in Laravel and Node.js. Involved both in team-based development and solo application building from design to deployment.

- Artetra: As an acting CTO, I translated business requirements into project features. I was responsible for the application architecture and occasionally handled smaller tasks. I managed a team of 3-4 developers and provided them with necessary assistance.
- ElectroRent: Developed and maintained Laravel code to fix bugs and add new features for a tool-renting platform.
- Aliat Optic: Designed and developed an invoicing app, integrating external FTP data via AWS Lambda and DynamoDB. This application was successfully used in production for about 3 years with minimal bug fixes.
- Hurlingham Club: Led the migration of systems to internal servers, resolving various DevOps issues.
- TicketTailor: Improved the API of a large ticketing application by fixing bugs and adding new features.
- Green Hardward Stranger Stranger

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer at

Cloud Based Compliance Management System.

- Developed the main API of the system and contributed to designing the ecosystem's architecture. Worked
 on all adjacent applications, which were deployed as serverless functions on AWS using Laravel Vapor.
- Developed a reporting application that enabled non-technical stakeholders to preview any key metrics

- Also built a bespoke real-time caching system that stores processed relational data in a NoSQL database.
 The purpose of this was to vastly increase the speed of the system and reduce the load on the database.
- Technologies: Laravel, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VuelS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Software Engineer at

Designing and developing our main applications and maintaining the AWS infrastructure.

- Led the migration from a NoSQL database to a relational database, resulting in an 11x speed increase without affecting the frontend or user experience.
- → Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, AWS, Loopback, pm2, Angular

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

Application Developer / Dev-Ops at

The only Backend Engineer in the company, I was designing, developing & supporting client applications.

- Developed and maintained nationwide educational platforms, enhancing the learning experience for thousands of users.
- Built a comprehensive financial management application with Laravel and Vue, streamlining financial operations.
- Managed all DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup on Forge, ensuring reliable and efficient deployment processes.
- → Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, MySql, VueJS

PROJECTS (2) -

CLI Path

https://iosifv.github.io/cli-path/

Simple CLI tool to search paths on google maps (Serverless Framework, Auth0, OpenAPI, VHS)

Casa4 website

An overengineered personal website built for learning purposes (Hugo, Terraform, Cloudfront, AWS, GHA)

EDUCATION (2) -

2010 - 2012

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

2004 - 2009

Masters Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

INTERESTS -

Hobbies

Chess HiFi Music

Motorcycles Photography

Boxing